我不知道这里有人
I didn't know anybody was in here.
你在找罗德尼么
Are you looking for rodney?
我看到他在餐厅
'cause I saw him in the mess hall.
罗德尼
Rodney?
对  你还好吧
Yup. are you all right?
还好
Yeah.
你看起来有点...  迷茫
You just seem a little... confused.
你病了么
Are you ill?
没
No.
没没没  我只是
No, no, no, I just, uh...
我...
I-- don't...
我在哪啊
Where am i?
你在辅助实验室里
You're in one of our auxiliary labs,
东翼  第四层
East pier, level four?
坐吧
Here, why don't you sit down?
没事
It's okay--
坐吧坐吧  我会通知罗德尼  只是...
No, really. I mean, I'll radio rodney, I'll just--
不不  你不需要那样做
No, no, you don't need to do that.
那好  你躺下吧
Better yet, let-- why don't you lie down?
跟我去医务室吧
Walk with me to the infirmary,
帮你检查检查
And they'll examine you,
他们会  他们会...
They'll-- they'll-- they'll...
看看有没有
Just see if there's anything--
你在这啊  我到处找你呢
There you are! I've been looking all over for you.
你的对讲机坏了么  我呼叫了N次
Is your radio not working? I called, like, 1,000 times!
我
Um... i--
我只是想检查一下你的通讯器
I just want to check your earwig.
来吧
Here we go.
好了
There we go...
大概是没电了
It was probably just a dead battery.
来吧  今天吃炸肉排
Come on, it's schnitzel day.
得赶快  晚了就没了
We've got to hurry, though, 'cause it's going fast.
怎么了
So what happened?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我们约了一起吃午餐啊
Well, hello? our lunch date?
你半个小时前
You were supposed to meet me, like,
就该来找我了
Half an hour ago.
我大概忘了
I must have forgotten.
怎么了
Hey. what's wrong?
你看起来心不在焉的
You seem distracted.
有什么事么
Is something bothering you?
我做了什么
Did I do something?
肯定是我做了什么
Oh... I did, didn't i? what'd I do?
没什么  我只是...  我没
Nothing. I'm just... I'm not--
凯勒医生
Dr. keller?
凯勒医生  请回答
Dr. keller! please respond.
等等
Just a second.
找你的
It's for you.
显然  公事第一
Working fine, apparently.
你好
Uh, hello?
凯勒医生  紧急情况
Dr. keller, we have an emergency.
泽兰卡博士受了重伤
Dr. zelenka has been seriously injured!
泽兰卡博士
Dr. zelenka?
泽兰卡怎么了
What's wrong with zelenka?
他还在抱怨
Is he complaining about
所谓的偏头痛么
Another one of his so-called migraines?
如果是的话  你就直接把他打发到...
'cause, if he is, you can just send him right down to the--
他被人刺伤了
He's been stabbed!
什么  刺伤  什么意思
What? stabbed? what do you mean, stabbed?
被刀子刺伤了?
Like, with a knife, stabbed?
谁刺的
By whom?
不知道  我们刚刚接到通知
I don't know, an s.o. just radioed us.
他被发现躺在实验室里
They found him on the floor of his lab.
没有知觉  大量失血
He's unconscious, losing a lot of blood.
他被送到医务室
They're rushing him to the infirmary.
好  我们马上过去
All right, we're on our way.
血压在下降  60跌倒40
His pressure's dropping. 60 over 40.
脉搏很快  大量出汗
Pulse rapid, skin diaphoretic.
扫描显示内出血
The scan shows internal bleeding,
肝被刺破了
Laceration of the liver.
那  他会死么
So, what-- is he going to die?
需要马上动手术  他失血过多休克了
He needs immediate surgery. he's in hypovolemic shock.
医生
Doctor?
是  是  他得动手术
Yes. yes, he needs surgery.
我们在准备手术室
We're prepping the o.r.
麦克布莱德医生做你的助手
Dr. mcbride will assist you.
他已经在消毒了
He's already scrubbing.
你准备好我们马上开始
We'll be set to go as soon as you're ready.
珍妮弗
Jennifer...
Jennifer!
你很奇怪  你怎么了
You're acting weird. what's wrong with you?
没事
Nothing.
没事  我去准备了
Nothing. I need to get ready.
医生
Doctor?
我不舒服
I'm not feeling very well.
你们继续
Take over for me.
我要去躺一下
I'm going to go lie down.
怎么了
How'd it go?
他们已经止住流血
They've managed to stop the bleeding,
但他流了很多血
But he's lost a lot of blood.
他醒了么
Is he awake yet?
没  他还在昏迷
No. he's in a coma.
轻度昏迷
It's a light coma.
他们认为他会好的
They figure he should recover,
但不能防止并发症
Barring any, you know, complications.
听说不是凯勒医生主刀
I hear dr. keller didn't perform the surgery?
是的  她找借口离开了
No. no, she... excused herself.
她说她不舒服
She said she wasn't feeling well.
她怎么了
What's wrong with her?
不知道
You tell me.
她今天很奇怪
I mean, she's been acting strange all day.
太虚神游  心不在焉
Aloof, distracted.
我看见她在城里乱逛  好像迷路了
I found her wandering atlantis, looking lost.
然后我带她到医护室
Then I got her to the infirmary,
但她只是站在那
But she just stood there
好像从没用过手术刀
Like she'd never held a scalpel before.
她现在在哪
Where is she now?
在她寝室  休息
In her quarters, resting.
贝克特博士马上要回来了
Dr. beckett is due back soon.
我会让他替她检查  以防传染
I'll have him examine her for any possible contagion,
或者  别的什么寄生生物
Or, god forbid, another one of those parasitic organisms.
以防万一
Better safe than sorry.
有线索么  谁会对泽兰卡博士下此毒手
Any leads yet as to who might have done this to dr. zelenka?
没有目击者  没有挣扎的迹象
No witnesses, no sign of struggle.
我要全面调查
I want a full investigation.
充分利用资源  全力以赴
Use every resource, no stone unturned.
我们的人昏迷了
One of our people is lying in a coma--
轻度昏迷
Light coma.
我要知道谁该负责任
...and I want to know who's responsible.
到底怎么了
What the hell's going on here?
听说你不舒服
Heard you weren't feeling well.
没
No.
我能进来么
Can I come in?
可以
All right.
你怎么了
So. what's wrong with you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只是  很累
I'm just... tired.
你给自己太大压力了
Been pushing yourself real hard lately.
是的
Yes...
你知道的
Well, uh, you know me.
我总是给自己很大压力
I'm always pushing myself real hard.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
总之
Anyway,
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
我只是要
I just need some--
有打扰你们么
Am i... interrupting?
没
No.
很好  我是说...
Good. I mean, um...
我只是顺便来告诉你
I just dropped by to let you know that, uh,
贝克特在回来的路上
Beckett is on his way back.
你病的时候  他会暂时代替你
He'll be able to fill in for you while you're, um... ill.
很好
Great.
对  我们
Yeah, we've, uh,
派了架小飞船接他
Sent a puddle jumper for him.
小飞船
A puddle jumper?
他在某个偏僻荒凉的村里
Well, he's in some remote desert village,
离星门十万八千里
And it'll take too long to walk back to the gate,
所以得搭个顺风车
So, it's easier to, you know, hitch a ride.
顺风飞船
A ride on a puddle jumper.
没错
Yeah.
也许我们该走了吧
Maybe we should leave,
让她好好歇歇
You know, let her get some rest?
好
Yeah.
有什么需要  通知我
Call me... if you need anything.
我会的
I will.
没什么反常的
Nothing out of the usual,
没外伤  没被寄生
No sign of trauma or any kind of organism.
血液循环呢
What about her blood work?
正常
The same.
你这样多久了
How long have you been feeling like this?
一天左右吧
Um... a day or so?
你睡得好么
Have you been sleeping all right?
不好  我给自己太大压力了
No. I've been pushing myself real hard.
今晚你最好待在这儿
Aye. well, I'd like to keep you overnight
以便观察
For observation.
吃点帮助睡眠药
I'll give you something to help you sleep,
我会监控你的状况
And we'll monitor your condition.
顺利的话
Then, hopefully,
你明早醒来就没事了
You'll wake up in the morning refreshed,
和以前一样  好么
Back to your old self. okay?
你真的什么都没发现
You're certain you saw nothing at all?
她没事
She's fine...
生理上没事
Physically speaking.
要说她有什么问题的话
If there's something wrong with her,
问题最有可能
I'm afraid it's most likely
出在心理上
Psychological in nature.
你好
Hello...
这些走廊
All these corridors,
搞的我晕头转向
I keep getting turned around.
小飞船在哪儿
The puddle jumper is... where?
飞船停泊舱
The jumper bay?
对
Yes.
中心塔顶层
Top of the central tower.
对  没错  我知道
Right. yeah, I know that.
我只是需要  我怎么...
I just need to, um-- how do i...?
传送器在走廊的末端
Oh, the transporter's at the end of the corridor.
它会载你过去
It'll take you there.
传送器  当然  谢谢
Transporter. of course. thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
太好了
Ah... perfect.
快  快  快
Come on, come on. come on.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我  睡不着
I... couldn't sleep.
什么  所以你就到停泊舱来了?
What, so you came up to the jumper bay?
对  我想逛逛
Yeah... I thought I'd go for a ride.
在小飞船里
In a puddle jumper?
有问题么
Is there a problem with that?
有点  首先你没有古人基因
A few. for starters, you don't have the ancient gene,
你不能驾驶它
So you can't fly one.
但是这你知道啊
But you already know that.
那你能驾驶么
Can you fly it?
当然  但这不是重点
Of course I can, but that's not the point.
听着  你该回医务室
Look, you should be back in the infirmary.
但你能带我去飞一下
But you could take me for a ride.
什么  现在
What, now?
对  帮我放松放松
Yeah. it would really help me relax.
贝克特给你吃过药了吧
Well, I thought beckett gave you pills for that?
没用
They didn't work.
来吧  求你了
Yeah. come on. please?
只有你和我
Just you and me.
单独的
Alone...
你可以带我去个僻静的地方
Oh, you could take me somewhere secluded.
我们可以在星空下
We can... we could make love...
做爱
Underneath the stars.
真的
Really?
你不想么
Would you like that?
当然
Well... yeah!
我得去拿毛毯
I mean, I'd have to get a blanket, though,
因为在陆地上
Because the mainland's groundcover
我对很多东西过敏
Is loaded with allergens.
不要  我们现在就走
No. let's just go now.
等等等一下  不行
Wait. w-w-wait. no, no, no, no.
听着
Look, you look.
你应该马上回到医务室
You should go back to the infirmary.
忘了医务室吧
Forget about the infirmary.
我想和你在一起
I need to be with you.
珍妮弗  别这样
Jennifer, please.
来嘛  就逛一会儿
Come on. just a quick ride.
难道你不想和我在一起
Don't you want to be with me?
不  当然不是  我只是
No. no! no, I just--
我想  我只是  你能不能停一下
Yes! I just-- will you stop?
我不知道你怎么了
Look, I don't know what's wrong with you,
但显然现在的你不是你自己
But you are clearly not yourself.
我带你回医务室
I'm taking you back to the infirmary--
不
No.
随你怎么吵
Well, you can argue all you want,
但我不会让你...
I'm not letting you--
我不跟你去任何地方
You're not taking me anywhere.
珍妮弗  听我的
Jennifer... I need you to listen to me.
你一旦痊愈
As soon as you are cured
或者那个影响你的东西没了
Of whatever it is that is affecting you,
你一定会为此感谢我的
You're going to thank me for this,
所以...  我们走
So... let's go.
不  你别...
No! don't you--
你在干什么
What're you doing?
你应该带我飞的
You should've taken me on that ride.
我不管扫描结果怎么说
I don't care what the scans say...
要么是她遭受了
Either she's suffered
严重的脑部损伤
A serious mind-altering brain trauma,
要么就是有什么东西控制了她
Or some kind of entity has taken control of her.
她最近有受过伤么
Has she been injured recently?
据我所知没有
Not that I know of.
昨天为止她一直很好
I mean, she was perfectly fine up until yesterday.
我告诉过你
I'm telling you,
脑部扫描能够显示
Her brain scan would have revealed
任何物理损伤
Any kind of physical trauma,
和各种异体寄生
As well as any foreign organism.
除非那种物质很会捉迷藏
Unless the organism's good at hiding.
是啊  不是第一次了
Yeah. wouldn't be the first time.
我们花了几天才发现罗德尼被感染了
It took days to figure out rodney was infected.
我还是觉得我们不能轻易地
I still don't think that we should rule out
排除心理创伤的可能
The possibility of a psychological event.
有时候我们都忘了
We sometimes forget that working
在另一个银河  这样的环境中工作
In this environment, in a whole other galaxy,
对人的精神摧残很大
Can be emotionally overwhelming.
这种压力经常会导致
Such acute stress has often been linked
各种各样的机能紊乱
To various dissociative disorders.
紊乱  她想杀了我
Disorder? she tried to kill me.
罗德尼  我不认为
Look, rodney, I don't think
她会扣扳机
She would have pulled the trigger.
我看得出她的眼神
Hey, I saw the look in her eyes.
她  等等
She-- wait a second.
她会不会和泽兰卡那事有关
What if she had something to do with zelenka?
或许是她刺伤了他
What if she's the one who stabbed him?
凯勒医生
Dr. keller?
躺那儿的女人绝不是珍妮弗·凯勒
That woman down there is not jennifer keller.
我觉得伍尔希是对的
I think woolsey's right.
有什么东西控制了她
Something has taken control of her.
我们怎么能肯定
How can we be sure of this?
我们可以先问问她
Well, we can start by asking her.
我们开门见山吧
Let's make this simple.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
什么
What?
如果你真是珍妮弗·凯勒
If you are, in fact, jennifer keller,
你就应该知道你从哪个镇来
You would know what town you're from,
你父亲叫什么名字
What your father's name is.
所以  告诉我们吧
So go ahead, tell us.
好吧
All right, look...
我知道我表现得有点奇怪
I know I've been acting strange--
奇怪
Strange?
凯勒医生不会拿枪指着我
Dr. keller wouldn't point a gun at me.
也绝不会刺伤泽兰卡
And she certainly wouldn't stab zelenka.
你干的  是不是
You did it, didn't you?
你刺伤了他
You stabbed him.
那是自卫
It was self-defense.
我不想伤害任何人
I didn't want to hurt anybody,
但他攻击了我
But he attacked me.
泽兰卡攻击你
Zelenka attacked you?
他不忍心伤害一只苍蝇
He couldn't harm a fly.
他要抓我
He tried to grab me.
我以为他要告发我
I thought he was going to turn me in.
我害怕被抓住
I was afraid of being caught.
事实就是
The fact of the matter is,
你被抓住了
You have been caught.
所以我建议你
So I would advise you
告诉我们你是谁
To tell us exactly who...
或者是什么
Or what you are.
我的名字叫尼娃·卡索尔
My name is neeva casol.
我一点不知道为什么自己会在这里
I have no idea what I'm doing here,
或者说在这个人的身体里
Or how I came to be in this person's body.
在她身体里
In her body?
是的  前一秒我还是自己
Yes. one moment I was myself,
在一个村庄里找史前古物
Searching through some artifacts in a village,
下一秒
The next moment,
我就跑进这个陌生女人的身体里了
I'm stuck in some strange woman's body,
站在这个城市的中间
Standing in the middle of this city.
每一次我看到
Every time I look
自己的影像  我看到她
At my reflection, I see her...
望着我
Staring back at me.
这怎么可能
How is that even possible?
我也希望知道
I wish I knew.
什么史前古物
What artifacts?
我和同伴
Me and my associates,
我们四处旅行  从一个星球到另一个
We travel around, planet to planet,
找一些值钱的东西
Searching for valuables to acquire.
也就是说  偷
Oh, you mean "steal."
我们听说了一个星球
We heard about a planet
很可能有珍贵的古人史前器物...
That supposedly held a trove of ancestral artifacts...
所以我们就去了那里  撬开地窖
So we made our way there and broke into the vault...
看见没  我告诉过你
You see? I told you.
这里有各种各样的珍宝
There is all kinds of treasure in here.
好了  动作快点
Okay, well, move fast.
只拿我们能搬的
Take only what we can carry.
那是  什么
What... is that?
不知道
I don't know.
不过这玩意儿太大搬不出去
But it's too big to haul out of here.
我不知道怎么回事  或者说为什么
I have no idea how this happened, or why.
相信我  我也莫名其妙
believe me, I'm just as confused by it as you are...
但我说的是事实
But I am telling you the truth.
我很抱歉袭击了你们的人
Look, I'm sorry for hurting one of your people,
但我很害怕
But I felt threatened,
碰到这种情况我只知道一种方法
And I only know of one way to deal with a threat.
我不想伤害任何人
I don't want to hurt anybody else.
我只想回到自己的身体里
I just... I just want to get back into my own body.
有什么发现
What have you got?
我想我大概知道怎么回事了
Well, I think I've figured out what happened.
那个女人说的史前古物
The artifact that woman described
我有印象  所以我做了些调查
It rang a bell, so I did a little research.
然后发现  几年之前
Turns out, a few years ago,
星门一队也碰到过类似的仪器
Sg-1 encountered a similar device
在格拉斯顿博里山洞
In the glastonbury cavern.
古人的通讯终端
The ancient communication terminal?
完全正确
Exactly.
当然了  那个石头  那种超自然连接
Of course. the stones, the psychic link--
什么终端机  什么石头
What terminal? what stones?
星门一队发现了一个古人仪器
ok,look. Sg-1 discovered an ancient device.
那些石头  如果你
These stones-- if you place them
把他们放进
In one of several recesses
仪器外围的凹陷处
Around the outside of the device,
就会激活它
It activates it,
能够让你联系上很远的人
And allows you to connect to someone far... far away,
能穿越银河  甚至说
Across the galaxy, intergalactically, even,
像丹尼尔·杰克森和娃剌这种情况
As was the case with daniel jackson and vala.
所以这女人激活了这种仪器
So this woman activated one of these devices?
我觉得是这样
I think so, yes.
那她为什么会连上凯勒
Why'd she connect with keller?
我第一个想问的也是这个
Ah, my first question as well.
然后我想到了杰纳斯的实验室
Then I remembered janus's lab...
在那儿我们修复了
We have recovered tons
大量的古人技术
Of ancient technology from there.
到现在还没编辑完
We're still in the process of cataloguing it all.
几周之前
Anyways, a few weeks ago,
我在那儿工作时珍妮弗来找我
Jennifer visited me while I was working there.
罗德尼  我们不快点走的话
Rodney, if we don't leave soon,
就没有好座位了
We're not going to get a good seat.
快好了
Yeah. almost-- almost there.
快点  那可是《007之诺博士》
Come on, it's dr. no!
邦德的第一部片子
The first bond movie.
你不会想
You don't want to get stuck
再坐在若楠后面吧
Sitting behind ronon again,
像上个礼拜那样
Like last week.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know, I know.
迟了连爆米花都没了
Not to mention, all the popcorn's gonna be gone.
上帝啊  这个太绝了
God! this is amazing!
设计初稿是关于
These are the initial design concepts
个人隐身装置的
For a personal cloaking device.
杰纳斯都没机会完成
Janus never got around to making it,
但要是给我足够时间  我可能...
But I think, given enough time, I might be able--
那些我们还没登记
We haven't cataloged those yet!
对不起
Sorry.
刚刚说到哪儿了
What did we say about that?
这些石头一定是和
These stones must somehow be connected
尼娃发现的古人终端机有关
To the ancient terminal that neeva found.
那珍妮弗又是怎么激活它的呢
But how could jennifer activate one of these stones?
他说得对  那是古人技术
He's right, it's ancient technology.
难道不需要古人基因么
Don't you need to have the a.t.a. gene?
可能已经被初始化了
Well, it must've been initialized already.
可能杰纳斯N年前就弄过了
Maybe janus did it thousands of years ago,
可能我们发现实验室后
Or maybe a tech initialized it
有技术人员初始化过它
After we discovered the lab.
关键是  珍妮弗显然是
Look, the point is that jennifer
最后一个碰到它的人
Was obviously the last person to touch this,
所以才会连上她
Which is why it connected to her.
如果我没记错报告的话
If I remember the case report correctly,
要取消这种联系很困难
Disconnecting the device proved difficult.
是的  我看了很多星门控制中心记载的相关资料
Yes. I've been going over the sgc files on that,
关于它怎么工作的  还有很多
And there's still a lot of unanswered questions
尚未解答的问题
About how it works.
等一下
Hold on.
如果说这个女人在凯勒的身体里
If this woman's mind is in keller's body,
是不是说凯勒在这个女人的身体里
Does that mean keller's mind is in her body?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能  应该说...很可能
Maybe. I mean... probably.
那问题就是
Then the question is...
凯勒医生在哪儿
Where is dr. keller?
怎么了
What happened?
你们联系亚特兰蒂斯了么
Did you contact atlantis?
没有
No.
为什么不
Why not?
我决定先联系一些我在其他星球上的
I chose to first contact a few of my trading partners
贸易伙伴
On other planets.
看来你和你的同伙
It appears you and your accomplices
臭名远扬啊
Have made quite the name for yourselves.
我告诉过你  我不是你想的那个人
I already told you, I am not who you think I am--
我觉得很幸运
I suppose I should feel fortunate.
你在这儿抢劫
I mean, your crimes elsewhere far exceed
远比不上在别处犯的罪
The mere robbery charges you've been accused of here.
在别的星球上
I've counted no less than five murders
你一人就至少背了五条命案
Committed on other planets by your hand alone.
死在你和你同伙手下的更多
Several more with the aid of your two accomplices.
也许他们暂且逃过一劫
Well, they may have eluded capture so far,
但记住我的话  我们会抓住他们的
But mark my words, we will find them.
听我说
Listen to me.
我是珍妮弗·凯勒医生
My name is dr. jennifer keller.
我是亚特兰蒂斯的首席医疗官
I am the chief medical officer from atlantis.
我不知道是怎么回事
I don't know what's going on,
我是怎么跑进这个女人身体里的
Or how my mind ended up in this woman's body,
但如果你联系他们  找罗德尼·麦凯博士
But if you contact them, ask for dr. rodney mckay--
据说你也是撒谎高手
You are also said to be a highly effective liar,
胡编乱造
Willing to fabricate any story,
说话不算话
Broker any kind of deal,
千方百计骗得自由
To get yourself free.
放心
Rest assured,
我不会上你当的
I will not fall for your tricks.
作为该村的地方法官
As magistrate of this village,
我将起诉你
I hereby pronounce sentence upon you
不仅仅在此星球
For the crimes you've committed,
还有联盟中的其他星球上
Not only on this planet,
所犯下的罪刑
But on all the other planets in the coalition.
明天
Tomorrow,
你将被带离牢房
You shall be taken from this cell
并处决
And executed.
怎么办
What are the options?
只有一个办法
There's only one option.
去那个星球
We have to go to the planet,
找到那个通信终端
Find the communications terminal,
关掉
And shut it off.
它是在那头被激活的  是最初的传输器
It was activated on that end. it's the initial transmitter.
所以只能在源头
The only way to sever the connection
切断连接
Is to shut it down at the source.
你有没有想到如何安全的关掉它
And have you figured out how to safely do that?
还不知道
No, not yet.
除非看到那玩意儿
We're not going to know
否则我们不可能知道
Until we get a look at this thing.
越快越好
Well, the sooner, the better.
我看了星门一队的报告
I've been studying the sg-1 report.
那个仪器不仅仅连通思想
This device connects beyond merely the psychological.
生理上也是相通的
There's also a physiological connection as well.
什么意思
What does that mean?
就是说  如果尼娃的身体死了
It means, should neeva's body be killed,
珍妮弗的思想就跟着陪葬了
Jennifer's mind would perish along with her.
我们就得终日与这个...
And we'll be stuck with...
霸占着凯勒身体的女人打交道
This other woman in keller's body?
我们得行动了
We need to get moving.
行
Agreed.
知道这个仪器在哪个星球上么
Do we know which planet this device is on?
会知道的
We will.
我很乐意带你们去
I would be happy to take you to the planet.
直接去找那个仪器
I'll lead you straight to the device...
但有个条件
On one condition.
你没资格提要求
You're in no position to make any demands--
什么要求
What is it?
你们切断连接后
When you sever that connection,
不许追捕我和我的同伴
You have to agree not to pursue me or my accomplices.
可以
Fine.
我还要一艘你们的小飞船
And I want you to give me one of those puddle jumpers.
什么  不可能
What? forget it!
我知道你们有很多  绰绰有余
I know how many you have. you have more than enough.
你啥都别想拿
You're not getting anything.
那就武器
Weapons, then.
你带我们去星球  我们就不追捕你
You take us to the planet, we agree not to pursue you.
就这么简单  接不接受
That's it. take it or leave it.
好吧好吧  我们走
All right, all right. let's go.
哪条路
Which way?
走这边
This way.
不远  几个小时的行程
It's not far. a few hours' walk.
几个小时
A few hours?
你不早说
You could have told us that before!
没大关系  罗德尼
Wouldn't have made any difference, rodney.
飞船又不能进森林
We couldn't get a jumper into this forest.
代达罗斯号在地球上
And the daedalus is back on earth.
是啊  但我可以带些
Yeah, but I could've packed
面包棍  带点水
Some extra power bars, some water,
换双软底鞋
Not to mention proper insoles.
他真能抱怨
He complains a lot.
只要他醒着一向如此
Only when he's awake.
他和凯勒医生真的...
Is it true that dr. keller and he are--
难以置信吧
Hard to believe, huh?
多走路少废话
Yeah, keep walkin'.
是时候了
It's time.
到了
That's it.
那个地窖中有大量史前古物
The vault containing the artifacts
就在村子中央
Is near the center of the village,
所以我们得轻轻的
So we'll have to be quiet.
我们最好别都去
Maybe only a few of us should go in.
而且我需要武器
And I'm going to need a weapon,
以防碰到
In case we run into some--
不用  我们不用私闯民宅
No. we're not breaking into the room.
什么
What?
去和村民谈
We're going to go talk to these people
向他们寻求帮助
And ask them for help.
是啊  他们当然会帮忙
Oh, they're not going to help us.
因为我洗劫过他们
I tried to rob them.
他们不认识你
They won't know you.
你现在是珍妮弗·凯勒  记得不
You're in jennifer keller's body, remember?
只要你守口如瓶
If you do not say anything,
就没有问题
It should not be a problem.
行啊  要是她...我被逮着了怎么办
Okay, but what if they've captured her-- me?
一旦切断连接
Once we sever the connection,
如何阻止他们把我关起来
What's to stop them from keeping me locked up?
没办法
Hmm... nothing.
Ahh. nothing.
你说我们不能追捕你
You said we couldn't pursue you.
不包括他们
Didn't say anything about them.
你阴我
So you tricked me.
安啦
Hey, just take it easy.
除非先告诉我  我的身体在哪儿
I won't let you disarm this device
否则我不会让你们切断连接的
Without first knowing where my body is.
你没的选
You don't have a choice.
同志们  时光在流逝
We're wasting valuable time here, people.
也许她应该留在这儿
Maybe she should stay here.
不  我要去
No. I'll go.
若楠
Ronon?
行  我看着她
Yeah, I got her.
出发
Let's go.
嗨
Hi.
放心  都是自己人
It's okay, we're friends.
我们  我们来自亚特兰蒂斯
We're, uh, we're from atlantis.
我是约翰·谢帕德中校
I'm colonel john sheppard.
你想要什么
What is it you want?
我们遇到点麻烦  需要帮忙
Well, we have a problem, and we need some help.
听说该村庄藏有
We hear that this village holds
大量古人的史前器物
A number of ancient artifacts,
特别是一个通讯终端
Most notably a communication terminal...
大大的  圆圆的
About yea-big, round-ish,
外圈有凹槽
Grooves along the outside...
有么
Yes?
你们为什么问起那个仪器
Why do you ask about this device?
就是说有咯  在哪儿
So you have it? where is it?
藏起来了  被严密保护
It's hidden, and well-protected,
你们若想带走它
So if you have any designs on removing it--
没有没有  听着
No, no, no, no, no. look.
我们就想看看
We just want to take a look at it.
我们认为它不小心被激活了
We think it may have become inadvertently activated,
而且  给我们造成了
And it's... well, it's causing some problems
不小的麻烦
For us on atlantis.
长话短说
Long story short,
我们来是为了关掉它  然后走人
We're just going to shut it off, and, well, we'll be on our way.
我们不是来惹事的
We're not here to cause any trouble.
是来寻求帮助的
We'd just like some assistance.
我无权帮助你们
I do not have the authority to grant such assistance.
你们得找村庄的地方法官谈谈
For that, you will need to speak to the village magistrate.
好吧  我们找他谈
All right. let's, uh, let's talk to him.
他不在
He's not here.
上帝啊
Oh, for god's sake.
他要去多久  这事儿很急
How long's he going to be gone? this is urgent.
死刑结束后他会回来的
He will return when the execution is completed.
我的天
Oh, my god!
尼娃·卡索尔
Neeva casol...
你因犯谋杀罪被起诉
You have been found guilty of the crime of murder,
并被处以死刑
And so you shall be put to death.
我不是尼娃·卡索尔
I am not neeva casol!
别担心
Don't worry.
刽子手很壮  刀刃很锋利
The executioner is strong, his blade sharp.
你痛苦远比不上
Your death will be far less painful
死在你手上的人
Than those of your victims.
别  别这样
Please... please! don't do this!
有埋伏
Ambush!
怎么
What?
连个谢字都没有
No thank-you for the rescue?
我们走
Let's go.
她朝那边跑了
She went that way!
快找
Find her!
去村子里再找点人
Go back to the village, gather more men.
看好祖传的戒指
I want that ancestral ring guarded!
不许任何人离开星球
No one leaves this planet!
真不敢相信  她怎么逃的
I don't believe this. how did she escape?
当然是拜我的同伴所赐
My accomplices no doubt intervened.
这种情况不是第一次了
This is not the first time we've been in this situation.
你有几个同伴
How many accomplices do you have?
两个
Two.
就两个
That's all?
足够了  相信我
More than enough. trust me.
你斗不过他们
You don't want to challenge them.
是么  走着瞧
Yeah? we'll see about that.
他们会去哪儿
Where would they have gone?
不知道
I have no idea.
好了  开始跟踪
All right, chewie. start trackin'.
这就来
Yeah. I'm on it.
你刚刚吓坏了
You looked frightened out there.
你认为我们会弃你于不顾
What, you didn't think we'd save you?
什么  没有  只是
What, that-- no, I just...
你救了我们那么多次
After how many times you saved our hides?
我们不会让你失望的
We weren't going to let you down.
你没事吧
You all right?
你有点迷茫
You look confused.
没有  我只是
No, I'm just...
得救很高兴
You know, happy to be out of there.
计划是什么
So, what's the plan?
计划
Plan?
是啊
Yeah.
我们现在怎么办
What do we do now?
我不知道
Uh... I don't know.
目前  还不知道
Yet. yet-- I don't know yet.
我  我需要
I-- I just need, um...
更多时间想
More time to think.
那快想
Well, think faster.
村民迟早会
Because, sooner or later,
发现这个山洞的
Those villagers are going to find this cave.
我可不想坐以待毙
And I don't want to be here when they do.
当然
Right.
有道理
Good point.
这边
This way.
十分钟内第三次搜察
That's the third patrol in the last 10 minutes.
看来整个村子都在找她
It seems as if the entire village is out looking for her.
希望我们能抢先一步
Let's hope we find her before they do.
到底怎么回事
What the hell happened?
跟丢了
I lost her.
没有踪迹
Are there no tracks?
什么都没有
There's nothing.
她很在行
She's good.
听着  我认为我们最好
Listen, I think the best plan of action
离开这个星球
Is to leave this planet.
我知道另一个星球
Now, I know of another planet.
很安全
We'll be safe there.
戒指会有人把守
They'll be guarding the ring.
我知道
I know.
也许可以来点别的
Maybe we could create some kind of diversion?
那要怎么做
Well, how do we do that?
我不知道
I don't know. um...
或许
Maybe...
可以弄个炸弹
Maybe we can set an explosion.
他们会朝炸弹跑么
And why would they run toward an explosion?
或者别的什么
Or something else.
我说等到傍晚
I say we wait till nightfall...
便偷袭戒指
...then we'll launch an attack on the ring.
出其不意
Catch them by surprise.
偷袭
Uh, an attack?
杀了守卫
We'll kill the guards,
激活戒指  然后跑路
Activate the ring, and we make our escape.
我同意
I agree.
好吧
Okay. uh...
但我突然想到什么
But if I think of something else before then,
或许可以
Maybe we could--
好吧  别开枪
All right, don't shoot.
你  是  谁
Who... are... you?
我是  尼娃·卡索尔
I'm... neeva casol.
好吧  我能解释的
All right, let me explain.
在那个地窖里
Back at the artifact vault,
我不小心激活了
I accidentally activated
某种古人通讯仪器
Some kind of ancestral communications device
导致我的意识被转移到这个女人的身体里
That caused my mind to transfer into this woman's body,
而她的意识在我这里
And hers into mine.
你觉得我们会相信么
You expect us to believe that?
你会的  杰尼克
Yeah, jannik, I do.
我知道你会相信的  就像你在瓦拉索尔
I expect you to believe that, just as you did on vara sol,
当我违背了和鱼商的交易
When I brokered that deal with the fish merchant
就为了救你
To save your life.
而你  布尔度
And you, bordal.
如果你不相信我
If you didn't trust me
那当你在窑子里被抓的时候
Back when you got caught at that brothel,
那些女人们
Those women would've made sure
绝对会废了你下半身幸福
The thought of procreating never again entered your mind.
这你是怎么知道的
How do you know about that?
因为我是尼娃
Because I'm neeva.
我和这女人是有关联的
There's a link between this woman and me.
我脑袋里是她的意识  她脑袋里的是我
Her mind is in my body, and mine is in hers.
不管在这里发生了什么
Look, whatever's happening here,
和我一点关系都没有
I had nothing to do with it.
是的  和她没关系
No, she didn't.
如果要解决这个问题  那就得赶快行动
But if we're going to fix this, we need to move fast.
必须得赶回那个小村子
We need to go back to the village,
去那个地窖  把仪器关掉
Break into the vault, and turn off that device.
我们必须非常小心
We need to be really careful,
不止那些村民在找我们
Because not only are the villagers out looking for us,
亚城的人  也在找我们
But so are the people from atlantis.
等等  他们来了?
W-w-wait a second. they're here?
谁  谢帕德中校?
Who, colonel sheppard?
还有其他人  他们会把我们交给村民的
Among others, but they'll turn us in to the villagers
如果不小心被抓
If they catch us,
所以  你不要给我们惹麻烦
So we need no problems from you.
明白?
Do you understand me?
好了  我们得找到那个仪器
All right, we need to find this device--
等一下
Stop!
我还是不明白到底怎么回事
I don't know what's going on here.
我告诉过你了
I just told you, all right?
我是尼娃
I am neeva.
我从来就没见过你
I've never seen you before!
杰尼克  听我说
Jannik, listen to me.
现在不是犯傻的时候
This is not the time to be stupid.
我不会惹他生气
Uh, I wouldn't make him angry...
把枪放下
You're going to put down the gun,
听清楚我说的
And you're going to listen to what I say.
不  我不听
No. I'm not.
你们通通跟我走
I'm going to take the both of you with me.
现在就去偷袭戒指
We're going to attack the ring now.
然后我们会搞清楚  到底谁是谁
And we'll sort out who's really who on another planet.
如果你骗我  那你死定了
And if you're lying to me, you're as good as dead.
那个麦凯博士
This dr. mckay...
他怎么啦
What about him?
他配不上你
You can do better.
闭嘴
Be quiet.
杰尼克  我知道这很难相信
Jannik, I know this is difficult to understand--
一开始时我也接受不了
I was equally confused by it at the beginning,
可是你得
But you have to--
多少人
How many?
我不知道
I don't know!
我数了四个
I count four.
如果你给我们武器  情况会好很多
We'd be a lot better off if you'd given us weapons.
他死了
He's dead.
嘿  退到这儿来
Hey! come back here!
别
Stop!
杰尼克  住手
Jannik, don't! don't!
她会没事么
Is she going to be all right?
目前不会  得先给她止血
Aye, for now, but I need to stop the bleeding.
罗德尼  扶着她
Here, hold her steady, rodney.
你们两个  帮个忙
You two, give us a hand here, please.
放桌子上  罗德尼
On the table, rodney.
这些人就是来自亚特兰蒂斯的
These are the people from atlantis
我之前跟你说过
I was telling you about.
发生什么事了
What happened?
她被你们的人打中了
She was shot by one of your men.
我警告过你
I warned you
到外面乱跑很危险的
It was dangerous to venture out there.
什么  她死了吗
What, is she dead?
没  只是受伤很严重
No, but she's badly wounded.
泰勒  帮个忙
Teyla, going to need a hand.
我得取出子弹  然后还得止住血
I need to remove the bullet and stop the bleeding.
我们得去找到那个通讯仪器
And we need access to that communication terminal.
马上把它关掉
We need to shut it down right now!
为什么  它干了什么
Why? what's it doing?
简而言之  它给这两人建立了精神上的联系
Well, simply put, it creates a psychic link between two people.
现在这个凯勒医生和尼娃·卡索尔
So dr. keller and this neeva casol
互相调了个
Have switched places.
都在对方的身体里
They're in each other's bodies.
你知道亚特兰蒂斯吧
You know about atlantis, right?
是的
Yes.
最好与我们为友
Then you know you're better off
而不是与我们为敌
Being our friend than our enemy.
那就表现的友好点
So why don't you be our friend
告诉我们那个通讯终端在哪儿
And show us where that terminal is?
这边走
This way.
它还开着
It's still on!
显然
Obviously.
那就关掉它
So turn it off.
没有开关啊
Well, there's no switches.
貌似和星门一队找到那个一样
But it looks almost identical to the one sg-1 found.
子弹取出
There's the bullet...
接下来就是止血了
Now to stem the bleeding.
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are...
但你肯定不是尼娃
But you are definitely not neeva.
是的  我不是
No, I'm not.
但我也不是你们的敌人
But I'm not your enemy, either,
只要你允许
And if you'd just let me,
我相信我能...
I think I can help--
你帮不了任何人
You're not helping anyone.
快点快点
Come on! hurry up!
我在试了啊
Believe me, I'm trying!
完全没法控制这个晶体
There's no way to access the control crystal.
好像根本没法关掉它
There doesn't seem to be a way to shut this thing off!
好吧  要不然  我们炸了它
All right. what if... what if we blow it up?
好吧  我不知道  或许可以吧
Well, I don't know. I mean, maybe.
我不确定  爆炸是否会引起
I'm just not sure if the explosion could cause
突然间能量波动
A sudden power surge--
那其他人怎么处理
What the hell'd the other guys do?
以前星门一队拨了号
Well, sg-1, dialed the gate,
把它丢到了逐渐成形的虫洞里
And tossed the device into the vortex
立马被分解了
Of the forming wormhole-- disintegrated instantly.
但这儿离星门太远  我们根本搬不过去
But it's too far to carry back to the gate.
你间接害死了布尔度
You got bordal killed.
也害我差点就死了
And you've almost got me killed.
我会以牙还牙的
I'm going to return the favor.
我们没什么选择的余地了
We may not have much of a choice,
那来帮忙搬一搬吧
So give me a hand with this.
不知道来不来得及啊
I'm not sure we've got the time--
等等
Hold up.
闪开
Move!
凯勒医生
Dr. keller?
泰勒
Teyla.
你回来了?
You're back?
我回来了
I'm back.
你中枪了  亲爱的
Shh. you've been shot, love.
别担心  子弹已经取出来了
Don't worry, we removed the bullet.
你会没事的
You'll be just fine.
等等  杰尼克
Wait, jannik.
是我啊  尼娃
It's me, neeva.
他们把仪器关掉了
They must've turned off the device.
想得美
Nice try.
杰尼克  不要!
Jannik, no!
谢谢你  丹娜
I appreciate that, dana.
代我问好
Say hello for me.
哇  这是什么日子呢
Well, well, well! what's the occasion?
就是来医务室看看朋友
Oh, just visiting a friend in the infirmary.
你真体贴  罗德尼
That's very thoughtful of you, rodney.
我知道
I know.
罗恩中士和他的分队已经回来了
Major lorne and his team just returned.
他们仔细检查了那个星球
They did a full sweep of the planet.
没有尼娃·卡索尔的踪影
No sign of neeva casol.
她肯定是跑掉了
She must've managed to escape.
这就不知道了
I don't know about that.
据珍妮弗说
According to jennifer,
她的同伙正准备杀了她
Her accomplice was just about to kill her
我们这时又刚好把仪器给关了
When we shut down the communication terminal.
好吧  她要么就是被同伙杀了
Well, either he did kill her
然后被抛尸荒野
And disposed of the body before escaping himself,
要么就是逃脱了
Or she got away from him somehow.
这就不得而知了
Well, I guess we'll never know.
我们会知道的
Well, we may.
已经放出消息了
Word has gone out
跟我们的同盟星球说过了
To several planets in the coalition.
如果尼娃确实还活着
If neeva is alive and roaming free,
那也活不久了
She won't be for long.
向我保证别太劳累了
You'll promise you'll take it easy?
会的  医生
Yes, doctor.
别担心  有我在
Don't worry. I'll make sure of it.
你好啊
Hey, you.
谢谢啊  罗德尼
Oh, thank you, rodney.
鲜花加巧克力  真让我感动
Flowers and chocolates? I'm impressed.
好吧  够了
Right. enough.
她孤伶伶的在医务室
She's all alone in the infirmary.
我只是觉得  我可以
I just thought I would, you know,
装点下房间
Brighten the room up a bit.
嗨  瑞迪克
Oh. hey, radek.
你怎样了
How you doing?
好多了  谢谢
Better. thanks.
瑞迪克  我真的很抱歉
Again, radek, I am so sorry for what happened.
那不是你的错
It's not your fault.
跟你说了  别担心
I told you, don't worry.
我很好
I'm fine.
是啊  他当然好
Yeah, yeah, of course he's fine.
看他红光满面容光焕发的  可以回去工作了
He's perky, rosy-cheeked, ready to go back to work.
我可不知道
I don't know about that...
他也需要休息  罗德尼
He needs to get rest, too, rodney.
我同意
I agree.
他受的伤比我严重多了
His wound was much more serious than mine.
真的么  可你中枪了
Really? I mean, you were shot.
他  只是被捅了一刀
He was just... stabbed.
要不我把你推到其他房间去吧
Perhaps I should wheel you to another room?
待到他走为止  多谢了
Just until he's gone, please. thank you.
是啊
Aye. right.
罗德尼
Rodney.
再同意不过了
I completely agree.
要吃巧克力么
Chocolates?
谢谢
Thank you.
我在想
So... I was thinking that, uh...
等你稍微好转了
When you're feeling better,
我们或许可以
We could maybe, um...
我们或许可以出去逛逛
You know, go for a ride.
逛逛?
A ride?
是啊
Yeah, you know,
找个小飞船  去大陆
Take the puddle jumper, go to the mainland,
然后野餐  或许可以
Maybe have a picnic, maybe...
躺在星空下
Lie out under the stars?
什么
What?
你确实关掉了
You did turn off
那个通讯终端么
That communication terminal, right?
怎么感觉像另外一个人了
There's no one else in there?
真的是我啊
No, it's really me.
那个坐小飞船去逛逛
'cause a puddle jumper ride
还有星光下的野餐
And the picnic under the stars...
我是说  有点太
I mean, that's just so...
我知道  不是我的风格
So not me. right, okay.
是个坏主意
No, bad idea.
不啊
No...
这主意很棒
I think it's a great idea.